Guide to the Hallie Flanagan Papers, circa 1890-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Hallie Flanagan Papers
circa 1890-1988
Flanagan, Hallie, 1890-1969
15.5 cubic feet (92 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Papers primarily concerning Flanagan's teaching and theater activities at Vassar College and her work with the Federal Theater Project. Includes correspondence, curriculum materials, scripts and other play records, reports, speeches, programs, playbills, photographs, scrapbooks, and clippings.
Biographical Note
Hallie Flanagan Davis, whose professional name was Hallie Flanagan, taught drama at Vassar, 1925-1942, and founded its experimental theater. She is more widely known, however, for her work in the 1930s as the director of the Federal Theater Project. She wrote several plays, numerous articles, and three books -- Arena, the story of the Federal Theatre; Dynamo, the story of the Vassar Theatre; and Shifting Scenes of the Modern European Theatre, the product of a year spent in Europe on a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1926.
Hallie Flanagan was born Hallie Mae Ferguson in Redfield, South Dakota. She graduated from Grinnell College in 1911. In her own words, "The main thing that happened to me at college was Murray Flanagan." Hallie Ferguson married Murray Flanagan in 1912, but her "rapturous" marriage ended with her husband's death from tuberculosis in 1919. After teaching high school, Hallie Flanagan taught English courses at Grinnell College and wrote plays. While teaching at Grinnell, she also assisted with performances of plays. Her own play, The Curtain, won a prize and helped her gain admittance to Harvard professor George Pierce Baker's 47 Workshop for Playwrights. In 1924 she earned an A.M. degree from Radcliffe. Upon returning to Grinnell, she produced some of her plays, which attracted the attention of Vassar's president, Henry Noble MacCracken, who offered her a teaching position at Vassar.
Hallie Flanagan's entire adult life was devoted to the theater as an educator, playwright, administrator, and director. From 1925 until 1942, she was a professor at Vassar. She founded and directed the Vassar Experimental Theatre, which was well known for the quality and originality of its productions. In 1934, during a sabbatical from Vassar, Hallie Flanagan directed the theater at Dartington Hall in England. She married Philip H. Davis, a professor of Greek at Vassar, in April of that year, keeping the name Flanagan professionally. In 1935 she took leave from Vassar to serve as director of the Federal Theatre Project, a unique effort in the history of American theater which staged over one thousand productions in forty cities. In 1942, Hallie Flanagan Davis went to Smith College as dean and professor of drama. She retired in 1955, at which time she moved back to Poughkeepsie. Hallie Flanagan Davis died in 1969, after a long struggle with Parkinson's disease.
Scope and Content Note
The collection primarily concerns her teaching and theater activities at Vassar College and her work with the Federal Theater Project and includes correspondence, curriculum materials, scripts and other play records, reports, speeches, programs, playbills, photographs, scrapbooks, and clippings. Correspondence consists of letters received and carbons of her outgoing letters to students and colleagues concerning her articles and books on the theater, the Russian theater, her experiences during a European trip, her Vassar classes, recommendations for her students, Theatre Arts Monthly, workers' theater such as the Arteff Theatre in New York, and other issues relating to the theater, 1925-1938. Correspondents include President Henry MacCracken of Vassar and her literary agent August Lenninger. There are also several letters from May Sarton concerning an amateur theatrical group she was working with and arrangements for a production at Vassar, 1933-1934; and two letters exchanged between Flanagan and T.S. Eliot about Flanagan's work and Eliot's suggestions for the setting, directions, and final scene for a production of his play Sweeney, 1933. Material on the Federal Theater Project consists of briefs, reports, scripts, playbills, and other printed matter.
Access
One folder in box 45 of this collection is restricted according to the Family Educational Rights and Property Act. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Federal Theatre Posters
Vassar College Archives Photograph Files
Vassar College Drama Department Records
Vassar College Office of the President Records, Henry Noble MacCracken Files
Subject Headings
Names:
MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Lenninger, August; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Sarton, May, 1912-1995
Organizations:
Federal Theater Project; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Vassar Experimental Theatre; Arteff Theatre (New York, N.Y.); Smith College. Department of Theatre
Subjects:
Performing arts--New York (N.Y.); Women in the theater; College theater--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Workers' theater--New York (N.Y.); Theater--Soviet Union; Theater--United States; Drama--Study and teaching; Federal aid to the theater; Experimental theatre; Amateur theater; Women college teachers
Places:
Europe--Description and travel
Document Types:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Playbills; Photographs; Printed ephemera; Scrapbooks; Scripts
VCL Categories:
Theater, Drama and Film; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, March 2007. Updated by Laura Streett June 2009 and April 2019. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, July 2025.
Acquisition Information
This collection includes two major accessions. Approximately 4 cubic feet were purchased from Joanne Davis Bentley in 1988. The other was a transfer from the Vassar Drama Department at an unknown date before 1988.
Six additional items were donated by Joanne Bentley in 2009: 2 letters from HFD (26 May 1930 and 16 June 1930), one diary fragment (beginning 19 Feb 1928), and a manuscript which is either a transcript of an interview with Shirley Rich Krohn or (more likely) a biographical piece written by HFD for "Dr. Wheelis" which was annotated by Shirley Rich Krohn. The other item is a folder of materials on Flanagan Bentley received by Bentley from the Federal Bureau of Investigation after filing a FOIA request. The items are now in folders 1.6, 20.161, 57.474a and 59.505.
Series X. 2025 Addition (Box 92), was the gift of Kathy Mendoza (VC 1965), collected by her mother, Barbara Mendoza. [M2025-008]
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1909-1987; (Boxes 1-17)
  Professional correspondence, 1910-1955, undated
  Vassar correspondence: interdepartmental and with students and parents, 1925-1941
  Federal Summer Theatre at Vassar correspondence, 1937-1938
  Personal correspondence, 1909-1967, undated
  Correspondence of others, 1918-1980, undated
  Correspondence to Joanne Bentley, 1969-1987
- Series II. Writings, 1904-1953; (Boxes 18-27, 60-91)
  Bibliographies and Autobiographical Essay, 1948, undated
  Travel notes/diaries, 1904, 1926-1934
  Notebooks, 1925-1927, 1936-1938
  Dramatic works, 1922-1953, undated
  Essays / articles, 1924-1952, undated
  Poetry and Fiction 1908-1935, undated
  Speeches, 1937-1944
  Shifting Scenes- printing plates, 1928
  Writings of others
- Series III. Printed Materials and Clippings, circa 1909-1988; (Boxes 28-43)
  Materials about HFD and her publications
  Federal Theatre Project: General
  Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Play Bureau Lists
  Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Service Bureau Lists
  Federal Theatre Project: Publications - Play Bureau Play scripts
  Dies Committee
  Grinnell College
  47 Workshop
  Pamona College
  Vassar College
  Smith College
  Miscellaneous articles on theater and dance
  Clippings and articles about others
  Unused postcards
  Miscellaneous printed materials
- Series IV. Institutional/Organizational Material, 1923-1969; (Boxes 44-48)
  Harvard University/Radcliffe College
  Miscellaneous
- Series V. Production Scripts and Materials, circa 1925-1953; (Boxes 49-51)
  Vassar Experimental Theatre
  Federal Summer Theatre at Vassar, 1937
  Federal Theatre Project, [193?]
  Smith College, [1944-1945, 1953]
- Series VI. Scrapbook, 1907-1911; (Box 52)
- Series VII. Photographs, circa 1890 - circa 1982; (Boxes 53-54)
  Professional
  Family
- Series VIII. Audio Recordings and Transcripts, 1967-1985; (Boxes 55-57)
  Interviews by Joanne Bentley
  Interviews by George Mason University
- Series IX. Family History and Biographical Material, circa 1916-1980; (Boxes 58-59)
  HFD: General, non-printed material
  HFD: Unpublished biographical essays/articles
  Family History
- Series X. 2025 Addition, 1909-1987; (Box 92)
  This series contains materials created by Hallie Flanagan, or about Hallie Flanagan and her work, that were collected by Barbara J. Mendoza during her research for her New York University doctoral dissertation, "Hallie Flanagan: Her Role in American Theatre, 1924-1935," 1976. Mendoza was given records related to Flanagan, the Vassar College English Department, and the Vassar Experimental Theatre, by the Vassar College English Department sometime around 1973. The series contains a mix of original and duplicate records created by Flanagan, the Vassar College English Department, and Mendoza.
Container List
For the reader's information: MS = manuscript; TS = typescript; TRS = transcript
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1909-1987
  - Professional correspondence, 1910-1955
    - The Short Stories Co. to HFD, 1910; (1 letter) (Folder 1.1)
    - To and from HFD, 1924; (2 letters) (Folder 1.2)
    - To and from HFD, 1925 Jan - 1926 Jun; (27 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 1.3)
    - To and from HFD, 1926 Jul-Dec; (16 letters) (Folder 1.4)
    - To and from HFD, 1927; (8 letters; 1 postcard) (Folder 1.5)
    - To and from HFD, 1928-1930; (10 letters; 1 postcard) (Folder 1.6)
    - To and from HFD, 1931; (13 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 1.7)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1932; (54 letters; 3 misc.) (Folder 1.8)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Jan-Mar; (49 letters; 4 postcards) (Folder 2.9)
    - To HFD from T.S. Eliot re Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Mar-May; (2 letters, M2006-002) (Folder 2.9a)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Apr-Jun; (40 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 2.10)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Jul-Aug; (31 letters) (Folder 2.11)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Sep-Oct; (55 letters; 2 postcards; 1 misc.) (Folder 2.12)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1933 Nov-Dec; (58 letters; 1 postcard; 5 misc.) (Folder 2.13)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Jan; (48 letters) (Folder 3.14)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Feb-Mar; (54 letters; 1 postcard) (Folder 3.15)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Apr-May; (45 letters) (Folder 3.16)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Jun-Sep; (39 letters; 1 postcard; 2 misc.) (Folder 3.17)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Oct; (50 letters; 2 postcards) (Folder 3.18)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1934 Nov-Dec; (40 letters) (Folder 3.19)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Jan; (42 letters) (Folder 4.20)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Feb; (33 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 4.21)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Mar; (52 letters; 3 misc.) (Folder 4.22)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Apr; (37 letters) (Folder 4.23)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 May; (40 letters; 2 postcards; 3 misc.) (Folder 4.24)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Jun-Aug; (40 letters; 2 postcards; 2 misc.) (Folder 4.25)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1935 Sep-Dec; (40 letters; 2 postcards; 1 misc.) (Folder 5.26)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1936; (30 letters; 3 postcards) (Folder 5.27)
    - To and from HFD and Vassar Experimental Theatre, 1937-1940; (36 letters) (Folder 5.28)
    - Federal Theatre Project: to and from HFD, 1936; (10 letters/memos - 1 original (6/13/36); remaining are photocopies, originals poss. in National Archives) (Folder 5.29)
    - Federal Theatre Project: to and from HFD, 1937-1938; (21 letters/memos; 1 fragment - photocopies, originals poss. in National Archives) (Folder 5.30)
    - Federal Theatre Project: to and from HFD, 1939; (20 letters/memos - photocopies, originals poss. in National Archives) (Folder 5.31)
    - To and from HFD, 1942-1955; (33 letters) (Folder 5.32)
  - Vassar correspondence: interdepartmental and with students and parents, 1925-1941
    - Interdepartmental business, primarily correspondence with President H.N. MacCracken, 1925-1932; (47 letters) (Folder 6.34)
    - Interdepartmental business, primarily correspondence with President H.N. MacCracken, 1933-1940, undated; (66 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 6.35)
    - Correspondence with students and parents, 1932-1933; (36 letters) (Folder 6.36)
    - Correspondence with students and parents, 1934-1935, May 1937, undated; (58 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 6.37)
    - Correspondence relating to Vassar Vocational Bureau, 1932-1935; (40 letters) (Folder 6.38)
    - Correspondence from Vassar students, classes of 1929-1941, collected by HFD for Dynamo, 1941-1942; (10 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 6.39)
  - Federal Summer Theatre at Vassar correspondence, 1937-1938
    - Administration: nominations, 1937 May-Jun; (27 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 7.40)
    - Administration: transportation for participants, 1937 Apr-Sep; (61 letters) (Folder 7.41)
    - Administration: notification letters to participants, 1937 Jun; (24 letters) (Folder 7.42)
    - Administration: room and board for participants, 1937 Mar-Aug; (27 letters; 3 misc.) (Folder 7.43)
    - Administration: general correspondence and memos, 1937 May-Jun; (18 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 7.44)
    - Administration: general correspondence and memos, 1937 Jun 16-27; (29 letters; 4 misc.) (Folder 7.45)
    - Administration: general correspondence and memos, 1937 Jun 28 - Jul 9; (66 letters) (Folder 8.46)
    - Administration: general correspondence and memos, 1937 Jul - 1938 Feb; (56 letters; 2 postcards; 1 misc.) (Folder 8.47)
    - Administration: payroll, 1937 Jun 25 - Jul 1; (21 letters) (Folder 8.48)
    - Administration: payroll, 1937 Jul 2-13; (30 letters) (Folder 8.49)
    - Administration: payroll, 1937 Jul-Aug; (60 letters) (Folder 8.50)
  - Personal correspondence, 1909-1967
    - John P. Ryan to HFD, 1909; (1 letter) (Folder 9.51)
    - Murray Flanagan to HFD, 1913; (1 letter) (Folder 9.52)
    - HFD to Deborah Wiley, 1917; (9 letters) (Folder 9.53)
    - HFD to Grinnell students, 1924-1928; (6 letters - 2 original) (Folder 9.54)
    - HFD to family, from Europe, 1926 Sep - 1927 May; (28 postcards) (Folder 9.55)
    - HFD to Vassar Experimental Theatre and individual students, from Europe, 1934 Feb-Mar; (12 letters) (Folder 9.56)
    - HFD to Vassar Experimental Theatre and individual students, from Europe, 1934 Apr-Jun; (12 letters; 3 postcards) (Folder 9.57)
    - HFD to Vassar Experimental Theatre and Esther Porter, from Europe, 1934 Feb-Apr; (26 pages) (Folder 9.58)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence, to and from HFD, 1932-1953 (Folder 9.59A)
    - Photocopies of material not owned by Vassar - most are letters to Lynne Anderson, 1938-1955 (Folder 9.59B)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt to HFD, 1952-1953; (3 TLS) (Folder 9.59C)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1935 May-Sep; (15 letters; 2 fragments) (Folder 10.60)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1935 Oct; (10 letters) (Folder 10.61)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1935 Nov-Dec, undated; (13 letters; 2 fragments) (Folder 10.62)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1936 Jan-Mar; (12 letters) (Folder 10.63)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1936 Apr-Jun; (9 letters; 2 fragments) (Folder 10.64)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1936 Jul-Sep; (6 letters; 1 fragment) (Folder 10.65)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1936 Oct-Dec, undated; (11 letters; 3 fragments) (Folder 10.66)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1937 Jan-May; (10 letters) (Folder 10.67)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1937 Jun-Oct; (10 letters; 4 fragments) (Folder 10.68)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1937 Nov-Dec; (14 letters; 1 fragment) (Folder 10.69)
    - HFD to Philip Davis, 1938 Jul - 1939 Feb, undated; (1 letter; 2 fragments; 1 postcard) (Folder 10.70)
    - HFD to Philip Davis: selected transcripts by Joanne Bentley, 1935 May; (2 pages) (Folder 11.71)
    - HFD to Philip Davis: selected transcripts by Joanne Bentley, 1936; (29 pages) (Folder 11.72)
    - HFD to Philip Davis: selected transcripts by Joanne Bentley, 1937; (28 pages) (Folder 11.73)
    - HFD to Philip Davis: selected transcripts by Joanne Bentley, 1935 [Jul]; (4 pages) (Folder 11.74)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: A-C, 1940; (42 letters; 2 cards; 1 postcard) (Folder 11.75)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: D-G, 1940; (52 letters; 1 card) (Folder 11.76)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: H-K, 1940; (29 letters) (Folder 11.77)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: L-N, 1940; (44 letters) (Folder 11.78)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: O-R, 1940; (27 letters) (Folder 12.79)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: S-T, 1940; (35 letters) (Folder 12.80)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: U-Z, 1940; (27 letters; 1 cards) (Folder 12.81)
    - Letters of sympathy to HFD after death of Philip Davis: unidentified, 1940; (18 letters) (Folder 12.82)
    - HFD to friends after Philip Davis's death, 1940 Feb-Apr; (4 letters - photocopies) (Folder 12.83)
    - Joanne Bentley to HFD, circa 1939-1943, 1964; (15 letters) (Folder 12.84)
    - Correspondence with Robert Baron, primarily HFD to RB, 1948-1953, undated; (31 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 12.85)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1955; (7 letters) (Folder 12.86)
      Note: Correspondents in Folders 86 - 103 include: Joanne and Eric Bentley, Fred and Betty Flanagan, Philip and Frances Youtz, Lynne Anderson, Lillian Berkeley, Emmet Lavery, Jane Matthews, Henry Allen Moe, Carlotta O'Neill, John Sollers, Patsy Walsh and Florence Wislocki.
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1956; (17 letters) (Folder 12.87)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1957; (6 letters) (Folder 12.88)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1958; (7 letters) (Folder 13.89)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1959; (4 letters) (Folder 13.90)
    - From Eleanor Roosevelt to HFD, 1959; (2 letters) (Folder 13.91)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1955-1959, undated; (7 letters) (Folder 13.92)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1960; (8 letters) (Folder 13.93)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1961; (10 letters) (Folder 13.94)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1962; (16 letters) (Folder 13.95)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1963; (13 letters) (Folder 13.96)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1964; (12 letters) (Folder 13.97)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1965 Jan-Jun; (17 letters) (Folder 13.98)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1965 Jul-Dec; (14 letters) (Folder 13.99)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1966; (15 letters; 1 envelope) (Folder 14.100)
    - From HFD to family and friends, 1967; (2 letters; 2 envelope) (Folder 14.101)
    - From HFD to family and friends, [196?]; (9 letters) (Folder 14.102)
    - From HFD to family and friends - Notes taken by Joanne Bentley, 1956-1961; (2 pages) (Folder 14.103)
  - Correspondence of others, 1918-1980
    - From Philip Davis to Jean Davis, 1918-1919, 1931-1934; (6 letters) (Folder 14.104)
    - From Philip Davis to E.C. Mabie, 1937, [193?]; (2 letters) (Folder 14.105)
    - From Philip Davis to Esther Porter [Lane], [193?]; (1 letter) (Folder 14.106)
    - From Peter Cox to Dorothy Elmhirst, 1947; (2 pages, TS extracts) (Folder 14.107)
    - Between Robert Baron and others regarding reprint of Arena, 1951-1960; (33 letters; 2 misc.) (Folder 14.108)
    - Regarding reprint of Arena - correspondents include: Frederic Flanagan; Duell, Sloan, and Pearce, Inc.; Eric Bentley; Benjamin Blom, Inc., 1963-1966; (24 letters; 2 contracts) (Folder 14.109)
    - From Joanne Bentley to siblings re: HFD, 1964; (1 letter) (Folder 14.110)
    - From Margaret Ellen Clifford to Eric Bentley, 1964; (1 letter) (Folder 14.111)
    - From Smith College students, collected by Helen Chinoy's Theatre Seminar, 1975; (TS excerpts - 21 pages) (Folder 15.115)
    - From Joanne Bentley to Virginia Deknatel and Vassar alumnae regarding HFD material, 1979-1980; (7 letters) (Folder 15.116)
    - From Grinnell College students to Audrey Koran, 1971; (5 letters - photocopies) (Folder 16.123)
  - Correspondence to Joanne Bentley, 1969-1987
    - Regarding Philip Youtz, 1980; (3 letters; 2 clippings) (Folder 14.112)
    - Letters of sympathy after HFD's death, 1969; (31 letters) (Folder 15.113)
    - Memorial service for HFD, 1969 Sep 16; (26 letters) (Folder 15.114)
    - Grinnell neighbors, 1979-1980; (15 letters; 1 fragment; 1 misc.) (Folder 15.117)
    - Grinnell high school classmates, 1980; (17 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 15.118)
    - Grinnell College classmates, 1979-1980; (5 letters) (Folder 15.119)
    - Relatives: William Lyle Flanagan, 1980; (5 letters) (Folder 15.120)
    - High school students of HFD in Iowa and Missouri, 1979-1980; (9 letters) (Folder 15.121)
    - People involved with George P. Baker's 47 Workshop and Radcliffe, 1980, 1982; (7 letters) (Folder 15.122)
    - Grinnell College Students, 1980, 1982; (15 letters) (Folder 16.124)
    - Pomona College friends of Summer, 1925, 1980, 1982; (3 letters; 1 misc.) (Folder 16.125)
    - Relatives about HFD and Philip Davis, 1980-1982; (12 letters) (Folder 16.126)
    - Vassar students about HFD and Philip Davis, 1980, 1987; (6 letters) (Folder 16.127)
    - About wedding of HFD and Philip Davis, 1980, 1985; (3 letters) (Folder 16.128)
    - Federal Theatre Project colleagues, 1980-1985; (16 letters) (Folder 16.129)
    - Vassar students, classes of 1928-1930, 1979-1982; (36 letters; 1 postcard) (Folder 16.130)
    - Vassar students, classes of 1931-1933, 1980-1983; (15 letters; 1 postcard; 1 misc.) (Folder 17.131)
    - Vassar students, classes of 1934-1936, 1980-1981; (14 letters) (Folder 17.132)
    - Vassar students, classes of 1940-1942, 1980; (6 letters; 1 extract) (Folder 17.133)
    - Vassar colleagues and friends, 1980-1982, 1987; (30 letters) (Folder 17.134)
    - Miscellaneous colleagues and friends during HFD's Vassar years, 1980, 1984; (3 letters; 1 postcard) (Folder 17.135)
    - Smith College students, 1979-1980; (6 letters) (Folder 17.136)
    - Smith College colleagues and friends, 1979-1987; (20 letters) (Folder 17.137)
    - Miscellaneous friends and acquaintances during Smith years, 1973, 1980-1981; (6 letters) (Folder 17.138)
    - Miscellaneous friends and acquaintances, 1955-1969, 1980; (2 letters; 1 fragment) (Folder 17.139)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1982; (1 letter) (Folder 17.140)
- SERIES II. WRITINGS, 1904-1953
  - Writings of HFD: Bibliographies and Autobiographical Essay
    - Bibliographies, undated (Folder 18.141)
    - Autobiography: Notes on my life, 1948; (MS) (Folder 18.142)
  - Writings of HFD: Travel notes/diaries
    - St Louis World's Fair, 1904; (MS diary) (Folder 18.143)